# Virasak SOKUN

Phone: +855 92 988 998 Email: sokunvirasak@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/virasak-sokun, Telegram/Whatsapp: +855 92 988 998

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

A Senior Business Analyst at Emerging Markets Consulting (EMC) with experience in project management, execution, and analytics. Skills in research and analysis, requirement analysis, and enterprise governance and architecture utilising proficient technical skills, excellent leadership skills, well-structured efficient project plan, and adaptability to changes in environment. Career goal is to become an experienced business analyst specialising in strategic development and digital transformation.

### **EDUCATION**

#### 2018 - 2020

### Master of Business Analytics, Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia

- A course developed for business analytics professional capable of driving business growth through analytics-based solutions
- WAM (weighted average mark) = 80.5 (High distinction)
- Member of Golden Key International Honour Society based on top 15% academic

#### 2012 - 2017

## Bachelor's degree of Economics, Pannasastra University of Cambodia, Phnom Penh

- GPA: 3.63/4.0
- 5% superior student (with dean's recommendation letter)

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Business Process Modelling, Process Map, Solving business problems
- Enterprise Architecture and Governance, business intelligence
- Digital proficiency: Microsoft Office, Microsoft SharePoint, Microsoft Teams, Zoom
- Data visualisation: Tableau, IBM Watson Analytics (with certificate), Interactive Visualisation
- Programming language: Python, R, SQL
- Analytics: Microsoft Excel, SPSS, RapidMiner
- Predictive analytics, marketing analytics
- Data mining: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, TensorFlow
- Graphic design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### Jan 2021 - Current

### **Senior Business Analyst**

### **Emerging Markets Consulting (EMC)**

- Work with clients with a diverse range of projects encompassing economics, business, market research, and industry and financial analysis
- Prepare project planning, define consulting tasks, manage project resources
- Develop tools, consulting products, and SOP related to administered projects
- Work across a diverse range of industries

#### Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

## Freelance Business Analyst, FlashFomo, Australia

- Interview clients to define business problems and propose data-driven solutions and requirements
- Gather requirements and automate the data collection process
- Analyst and provide data-driven recommendations and communicate technical concepts into plain languages for non-technical clients

### Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

# Research Assistant, CoronaNet Research Project, based in Germany

- Gather data related to government policy responses to COVID-19 pandemic within assigned countries and maintain accurate records for use by policy makers, academic researchers and others
- Assist with data cleaning and wrangling for the website
- Create interactive visualisations including maps and graphs for the official website

# **EMPLOYMENT**

- Provide high quality customer service and maintain satisfaction level
- Prepare and maintain correct and complete records related to products work activities
- Display and maintain products in an effective manner
- Work effectively in teams and cross-functional departments

### Nov 2017 - May 2018 Project Coordinator, STEM Cambodia Organization, Phnom Penh, Cambodia

- Directed Cambodia National Robotic Competition and increased high school students' inspiration to pursue STEM majors as a career goal
- Recruited project's team members and developed project's monthly milestones
- Managed communication with partners such as private sector companies, NGOs,
  Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports, British Embassy, US Embassy. etc

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

#### Mar - Jun 2020

## Team Leader Intern, Deakin TALENT FreelancingHUB, Client: Ambulance Victoria

- Liaised with client and supervisor to establish agreed scope of work and ensured the project efficiently delivered within three months
- Diagnosed problems with current rostering system of the Ambulance Victoria through gathering requirements, analysing data, and proposing digital solution with concrete project development timeline

#### Oct - Dec 2019

# Data Science Intern, FlashFomo, Melbourne, Australia

- Analysed and created data retrieval script using Python for social media analytics
- Visualised the data using Tableau and generated insights to guide future customers segmentation and products selection
- Constructed predictive model for future social media influencers selection using RapidMiner and Python

#### **VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE**

#### Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

#### **Project Core-Team Member**

# SEALNet Project Cambodia 2017 "Fostering Healthy Lifestyle", Siem Reap, Cambodia

- Provided access to clean water throughout Krobei Riel community by donating 20 hydraulic water filters and 13 bio-sand filter for public use
- Conducted leadership workshops for students (years 8-11) and equipped with knowledge to become community service leaders
- Solved internal and external project's issues with potential partners and secured project's sustainable plans
- Defined target beneficiaries through qualitative interview technique and generated insights
- Achieved public support and increased other project interests to continue to solve other issues

## **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS AND SPECIAL TRAININGS**

# Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

# Top 10 Finalist of the 2019 Global Analytics Competition

"The Exploration of relationship between air pollution and population"

- Collected and cleaned time series data using IBM Watson Analytics and other data analytics software
- Explored relationships between variables and generate insights
- Analysed keys factor of air pollution and suggested sustainable solutions to problems

#### **MEMBERSHIPS**

#### 2019 - Current

# **Proud Member, Deakin University Chapter**

Golden Key International Honour Society

#### **2016 – Current**

## Active Member, SEALNet Club Cambodia

- Support new service leadership projects and regularly visite communities
- Create leadership retreats plan to welcome new members

#### **REFEREES**

### (Available Upon Request)